Thursday, July 16th.
I'm never any good at these book questions.
Thursday, July 16th
I know I should concentrate
on figuring out the prose and
work through the questions without
trying to fully understand them,
but I just can't seem to do that.
The way people stress over not understanding
each other makes no sense to me.
I don't get it at all.
Yeah, I know. That just makes me weird.
Anyway, Asamura-kun is really
good at explaining things.
I had honestly kind of given up,
but thanks to him, I have hope again.
Thanks.
Friday, July 17th
Friday, July 17th.
The music he recommended is really great.
Asamura-kun went out of his way
to find something good for me.
I should thank him.
It's weird.
When I get in bed and close my eyes, my head
fills with all sorts of annoying thoughts.
Asamura-kun got that music from
his pretty senpai at work, right?
Not that it really matters.
But if I don't think it matters,
why bother writing about it in my diary?
Saturday, July 18th
I don't get it. No matter how I look at it,
it doesn't make sense.
I have no right to be
writing things like this...
yet I'm doing it anyway.
Who cares? I'm only doing this for myself.
Asamura-kun came home late today.
Something with a girl from work?
He didn't say anything to me about that.
Sure, I know. There's no reason for
him to report stuff like that to me.
Was it that same girl, I wonder?
If so, I hate this.
Yeah, when I write it down,
I feel like the words that come out on
the page don't match my true feelings.
But of the words in my vocabulary,
"hate" is the one that comes closest.
I'm so awful. I don't even
know anything about her.
It makes me sick of myself.
It's self-hatred. I feel so anxious.
For some reason, I wanted to welcome
Asamura-kun home when he got back,
so I decided to study in the living
room instead of my bedroom.
In the end, I couldn't stay
awake until he got home.
I didn't get to say "welcome home."
But I did wake up with a blanket on me.
I wonder if...
When I had that thought,
the anxiety I felt last night
seemed to clear up a little.
Sunday, July 19th
Yomiuri Shiori.
I think that's a really pretty name.
The kind of name that loves books,
is loved by books,
and is bound to be loved by
other people who love books.
Also, maybe it's because she's in
college, but she seems so mature.
And she's not just beautiful.
She also has a kind of adorable charm to her.
I really think they'd make a good couple.
If he could be with someone like that,
I'm sure Asamura-kun would...
Now Hiring Part-Timers!
If you're interested in books and publishing, why not come work with us?
Job Details
Duties: Sales, register, stocking, and inventory
No prior knowledge required
Open Positions: 3
Hours:
Schedule negotiable
Days: 2 to 4 days a week
Looking for cheery, energetic individuals. Ask an employee for details.
A bookstore, huh?
It isn't exactly an easy, high-paying job,
but instead of trying to take a shortcut,
maybe it'd be worth it to
do things slow and steady.
I don't know, though.
Maybe it would creep him out.
I know we're stepsiblings, but interviewing
for a job where your brother works
is kind of a weird thing to do.
Sunday, July 20th
Today was my last chance
to study before my retest.
I'm really grateful to Asamura-kun
and Maaya for helping me out.
I want to go to bed early and wake up sharp
so I can put my brain to work tomorrow,
so I'll keep this entry short.
The sweet 'n' sour pork was really good.
Thanks, you two.
I passed my retest.
Tuesday, July 21st
It's easy to say this now
that I have the results,
but honestly, I was already sure by
yesterday or so that I was going to pass.
It's all thanks to Asamura-kun.
And Maaya, too. I'm grateful.
At any rate, now I should be able to
spend my summer vacation as I please.
Now Hiring Part-Timers!
If you're interested in books and publishing, why not come work with us?
Job Details
Duties: Sales, register, stocking, and inventory
No prior knowledge required
Open Positions: 3
Hours:
Schedule negotiable
Days: 2 to 4 days a week
Looking for cheery, energetic individuals. Ask an employee for details.
I'll keep studying bit by bit
as I save up money from work.
Someone approached me as I was
looking at the help wanted poster.
Without thinking, I told him that,
yes, I was interested.
No taking it back now.
I could have practiced
for the interview at home,
but I figured it'd be really awkward
if Asamura-kun were around.
If he saw me, I'd probably die a little.
If he asked me why I picked
that bookstore in particular,
how would I even answer?
I honestly don't know myself.
How could I? There's no way...
I'm sorry to have worried you.
I knew I'd be late and thought
about letting you know,
but then I probably would've
had to explain why I was late,
so I couldn't say anything.
Sooner or later, I'm going to have to
confront this anxious feeling I keep getting.
To make up for what I did, I decided
to make him a really nice meal tonight.
I figured he'd be more likely to forgive me
if I treated him to some good food.
And even if he doesn't,
he'll at least have to accept it, I guess.
I'll convince him that I was late because
I stopped by the department store.
And saying I didn't see his messages
because my battery died should be okay.
The more I lie, the more I feel a seed
of doubt starting to sprout in my mind.
I'm scared...
of the feelings I'm having right now.
I think I have a good idea of what's happening
and how I'm starting to feel about him.
There's only one word to describe it,
...never expected that he attended Suisei, too.
and I'm torn as to whether
I should put it down in my diary.
...from his pretty senpai...
...that it really matters...
...don't think it matters,
why bother writing about it in my diary?
...don't get it.
...like I was thinking about him...
...I really regret that...
Yomiuri Shiori.
...really pretty name.
It's all too ironic.
I never dreamed I'd start behaving
like some character in a novel.
But I can't run away now.
The job interview was such a breeze.
I'm going to have to come clean to Asamura-kun.
I'm scared to explain it to him. I'm terrified.
But at the same time,
I think it will be a relief.
Of course it will be.
I mean, I'll finally be free of this anxiety.
There are parts of Asamura-kun I don't know.
There are parts of his relationship
with Yomiuri-san I don't know.
If I can at least get an idea of what those are,
maybe this gross, anxious
feeling will let up a little.
I think it will.
I really can't believe myself.
Why am I giving him control over my actions?
Asamura-kun hasn't done anything.
I'm the one who tied myself in chains
and bound myself to him.
Really, the whole thing is so stupid
it makes me want to laugh.
I'm not going to let anyone read this anyway.
Maybe as a sort of warning to myself,
I should go ahead and write the word.
If I hide it way in the back of a drawer
and lock it shut, it should be safe.
So here's a test question for you, Ayase Saki.
Describe the nature of the unpleasant
feelings you're experiencing in one word.
Saturday, August 22nd
It's all so delicious again today!
Oh, it's nothing special.
Here, Asamura-kun.
Thanks, Ayase-san.
So, Yuta and Saki-chan, you both still
call each other by your family names?
Episode 7 "Feelings and Summer Vacation"
Are you still too embarrassed
to use your given names?
Hmm, how about something
like "Big Brother Yuta"?
That just doesn't feel right.
No?
No.
Do you feel the same, Yuta?
I agree with Ayase-san.
It just doesn't feel right, I guess.
Hmm. Well, I suppose that's that, then.
Do you both have work again today?
Yes. I'm planning to leave by noon.
Me, too.
Are you sure you should be working
so much? August is already half over.
Don't worry. I've still been going
to summer cram school.
No, that's not the issue here.
It's summer vacation, and it doesn't
sound like you've gone anywhere for fun.
Oh, that's what you meant?
This is a big deal. Once you're a third-year,
you'll have to concentrate on exams.
That's right.
And I know you tend to push
yourself a bit too hard, Saki.
Your friends are probably
missing you both right now.
That's not that many people.
Oh, for me, I mean.
Ayase-san has friends, though.
We don't have any plans.
Come in.
If you meant Maaya, don't worry about her.
Huh?
We're not so close that we'd
hang out over summer break.
Oh.
Sorry. I'm not mad or anything.
But Maaya and I don't really hang
out that much to begin with.
Even though she's come over a few times?
Well, that's because she was
really curious about you.
And also because I invited her,
like last time.
She's actually very considerate, so if we
don't make plans, she gives me my space.
I'm the same way.
Well, I can kind of understand that.
I don't like hanging out with people
I'm not that close to, either.
Do you like your solitude?
I think I do prefer it, yeah.
Okay.
I guess that's enough talk for now.
See you later.
Thanks.
No problem.
She's sure getting the hang of things quickly.
Thank you very much.
Is Ayase-san okay over there?
Go give her some backup.
Okay.
Ayase-san.
Asamura-san.
Did it show up in the search?
It says we still have five volumes left.
It's a new release, right?
And it wasn't on the display stand?
Right.
Just out on August 22!
THE BEEHIVE
TAMURA KANAE
Staff Pick!
Town on the Other Side of the Mirror
Madoka Yuki
THE BEEHIVE
TAMURA KANAE
Just out on August 22!
Staff Pick!
Town on the Other Side of the Mirror
Madoka Yuki
Oh, wow. How'd you know?
Your customer is waiting.
Right.
Thanks for your help today.
But really, how did you know?
It's like you were psychic.
The sign said that book was a
new release from August 22nd.
But I remembered that the
book on the top of the pile
had already been out for a while.
I didn't even notice.
Well, I do have a lot more experience.
I still think it's impressive.
Yomiuri probably would
have found it even quicker.
Oh.
I guess it's already fall.
I guess summer isn't over yet.
Huh?
Eh?
Do you mean because of this heat?
What did you mean?
Well, look over there.
That means... it's fall?
Are you being serious right now?
I mean, they were wearing
different clothes until yesterday.
They were?
No way. Asamura-kun, are you one of
those people with zero interest in fashion?
Have you ever seen me
reading a fashion magazine?
I guess not.
If you're not interested,
I guess you really wouldn't notice.
Looks like you're right.
Well, I can't imagine you working at
a clothing boutique, so I guess it's fine.
Where did that come from?
Never mind.
Sunday, August 23rd
It's broken?
Yeah. This is our oldest one, after all.
Is Ayase-san in her room?
Well, she was until just before you got up,
but she really doesn't
handle the heat very well.
Is that right?
It was a real problem when she was younger.
When summer came,
she'd always demand ice cream
and throw tantrums saying,
"Take me to the pool!"
Once she got into middle school,
that started to change.
She became more like she is now.
She stopped being such a handful,
but I still miss those old days.
My mom started working
twice as hard to provide for me.
Yes?
Yeah.
Yeah. Right now?
So anyway, Asamura, I heard you're going
to the pool with Narasaka and some people?
Huh? What are you talking about?
What? I'm talking about you and Ayase
going to the pool with Narasaka.
Haven't heard a thing.
Didn't you get invited?
Nope.
Then maybe they'll invite you later.
Yeah, maybe so...
Hey, aren't you short on time?
Oh, y-yeah.
Then we should go.
Lemme hit the bathroom first.
Sure.
Getting used to work?
Yes. Thanks to your help.
You're dependable and
a quick learner, Ayase-san.
Thanks.
The other employees were praising you, too.
Yeah?
I guess it is like my dad said.
Feels like we're spending
our whole break working.
Yeah.
Ayase-san.
By any chance, did Narasaka-san
invite you to go to the pool?
Did she maybe invite me, too?
Did Maaya tell you that?
No, Narasaka-san doesn't have my contact info.
Then how would you know about it?
Someone else told me.
I hadn't heard anything before that.
Do you want to go, Asamura-kun?
Huh? Uh...
To be honest, I think I'd feel out of place
at a pool with a bunch of cheery people.
Not really my thing.
Oh.
Ayase-san?
Then you don't need to force yourself to go.
Aren't you going? To the pool?
No, I'm not.
Starting tomorrow,
I'm going to be working at your store.
Why didn't you tell me you applied for a job?
It would've been embarrassing
if I didn't get it.
Asamura
Ayase
So here's a test question
for you, Ayase Saki.
Describe the nature of the unpleasant
feelings you're experiencing in one word.
"Jealousy."
Episode 8 "A Response and Hot Milk"